<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C Programming with ChatGPT</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/programming-with-chatgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/programming-with-chatgpt/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to experiment with ChatGPT and programming. So, I thought I would just start with an exercise from Kernighan and Ritchie&amp;rsquo;s The C Programming Language.&#xA;I prompted ChatGPT with the following:&#xA;In C write a program called detab that replaces tabs in the input with the proper number of spaces to reach the next tabstop. Assume tab stops every eight columns. This is exercise 1.20 from The C Programming Language by Kernighan and Ritchie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Modules</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/emacs-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/emacs-modules/</guid>
      <description>Emacs is implemented in elisp (most of it). Extending, modifying or customizing emacs is also done in elisp. (However, some of emacs is written in C.),&#xA;As of Emacs 25 it is possible to extend emacs by writing modules in C.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a simple example using the notes from https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Module-Initialization.html&#xA;Start the Module A module must start with the following:&#xA;#include &amp;lt;emacs-module.h&amp;gt; int plugin_is_GPL_compatible; After that, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy to create a test function.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The C Programming Language</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/this-is-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/this-is-now/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, I was on a reddit thread and someone commented that they knew python and wondered if they should learn C …&#xA;I thought everybody knew C! ;)&#xA;Back in the day, C was my third or fourth programming language.&#xA;With the mention of C I just had to break out my copy of The C Programming Language. Unfortunately, my original copy is long gone but I have the second edition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Documents</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/computational-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/computational-documents/</guid>
      <description>Not all the documents that I create are computational — but when they are I use Emacs, Org Mode, and Babel&#xA;Computational documents are a mixture of text and executable code. And the process of creating them, bringing together the text and code is called &amp;ldquo;weaving.&amp;rdquo; But sometimes, you want to separate the text and code. This is called &amp;ldquo;tangling.&amp;rdquo; For more see, extracting source code.&#xA;This turns out that tangling is pretty useful when you want to maintain one source of code for display and for processing, maintaining the DRY principle</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s a Lambda?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/whatisalambda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/whatisalambda/</guid>
      <description>This document is a brief investigation into the question:&#xA;What is a lambda?&#xA;And, in our context, more specifically, what is lambda in computer languages, and even more specifically, what is lambda in Java.&#xA;Java added lambda expressions in 2014 (see Java SE 8).&#xA;Caveat: Nothing in this document is meant to be exhaustive. It&amp;rsquo;s not the final word on anything. And there most likely are errors in it – in fact, most definitely.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
